welcome back
today we are going to complete the last challenge of GregTech New Horizons
which is crafting a Stargate
this things is going to require many items
with many sub steps
but it all boils down to three main parts
the main issue other than the expensive materials used is the time required to craft those
to craft this stuff in a reasonable time
we are going to do some overclocks
but the real question is how much we should overclock
if we don't want to end up with a blackout
or waiting times longer by magnitudes
we must find the optimal compromise
to find the answer
we first have to figure out
how much energy we can produce
and while looking for a good generator
our attention was caught by the shielded Legrandian annihilation matrix
a generator that runs on antimatter
of course
the question now is how do we make antimatter
and how much we can make
and it turns out
it's made in one of those complex to manage multi blocks
the semi stable Antimatter Stabilization Sequencer
after quickly building it
and getting some antimatter to kick start the machine
it is time to have some fun
the first and most important thing we notice is that
we must keep the antimatter evenly spread across the hatches
and doing so is no joke
anyways
to do a little test
we start by spreading our antimatter across all of the hatches
then after a bunch of tests
we got to a point where we noticed how often we have to carefully find which hatch lost antimatter
and after realizing that a simple cover won't be enough
we did an SFM program
that will keep a fixed amount of antimatter in each hatch
with that
we can now slowly build up some antimatter
which we will then spread evenly across all the hatches once again
the more antimatter we keep in the machine
the more we will produce
but also the more energy will be used
the question is now
how much antimatter we should keep in each hatch
to find an answer
we can give a purpose to the calculus class we had to take in school
we shall plot the amount of energy in function of how much antimatter we place inside each hatch
the blue line represents how much energy we can make with the produced antimatter
while the red line will tell us how much energy that costed us
we want to maximize the energy gain
meaning the difference between the two lines
which we can see here as a single function
and the maximum we can get out of it is four Dyson spheres worth of energy
by keeping two and a half buckets of antimatter in each hatch
however
by increasing the containment stabilization
the activation stabilization
the gravity stabilization
and the magnetic stabilization
we managed to make our energy gain graph go out of the screen
after some zooming
we find out that our production can now reach 600 trillion EU/t
by leaving 4 million antimatter in each hatch
and adding a bunch of other expensive stuff
and that is one huge ball of antimatter
to turn it into energy
we are going to need one more machine
which isn't as complicated as the other one
one of the main requirements is to feed it with balanced amounts of materials
which we can easily do with the same set up we used to feed the eyes of harmony
this time the optimization problem is that
we should insert as much fuel as possible in each batch
but we are limited by the capacity of our lasers
with 16 UIV 1 million amps lasers
we can produce as much as 100 Dyson Spheres
but if we switch to UMV 4 million
we can fill up an ultimate battery in 5 minutes
that causes a bunch of issues
but the best way to solve every problem
is to use a better reactant
and turn on wireless mode
the takeaway is that
assuming we build a dozen of antimatter sequences
our whole energy production is going to be about 5 quadrillion EU/t
a number with 15 zeros
and from that
we can get an idea of how much power
we can throw at machines
with that
we can now start working on all of the issues we will face while working on our star gate
and the first problems started arising just when we were working on our new power production
to have a high power output
we had to insert various fluids in the antimatter sequencer to stabilize it
while some are either expensive stuff or byproducts
a curious one was the depleted naquadah fuel
after upgrading our fuel production
we turned on full time our backup generators
but it appears that those aren't burning fuel fast enough
so we had to opt for a different way of wasting fuel
energizing tesseracts
that is a slow process
but luckily
the oversized neutron activators we did for Naquadria
have the same kinetic energy working range
after fixing the antimatter production materials
we also realized that to react it efficiently
we are using liquid UMV superconductor
the main issue here is that
this stuff contains dragon blood
which we make with the draconic Evolution Fusion Crafter
and that machine has a couple of issues
the first one being that like many other machines
it won't accept multiamperage energy hatches
which means that we won't be able to overclock it as much as we do with other machines
that usually means we just have to spam many of it
but there is a second issue
each Fusion Crafter requires a dense Gaia Spirit plate
meaning we have to defeat more than two of the super annoying botania bosses for each machine of our array
however
while working on that annoying task
something gave us an idea
it appears that there is a mob with a high chance of dropping spawns
with those we can craft dragon eggs
which can be turned into dragon blood with a normal mixer
all we have to do is find the correct mob
and start farming it in an industrial way
so that we can produce industrial amounts of spawns
eggs
and dragon blood
now that we have fixed the energy production
it is time to craft some energy hatches to put it to good use
and here
we realized that our universium production is too low
to fix that
we are going to need a couple more of Astral Array fabricators
and now the issue is the size of our crafting units
so I guess it's time for us to get a singularity crafting storage
and if we want a bunch of those
we will need to go and take down a couple of Chaos Guardians
from each Guardian
we get one of those crafting units with 8 exabytes of storage
but now we lack of co processing units
instead we shall make better patterns
with the new Pattern Optimization matrix
that is because co-processors are needed to increase the amount of crafting steps done each second
but instead of doing more steps at once
we can make bigger steps
to do so
we multiply the patterns with the help of the optimization matrix
which will make it so it won't take more steps than the amount we specify
however
doing so will also cause a lot of leftovers
which are now filling up all of our storage cells
so we are going to upgrade to the artificial universe ones
crafting one of those takes a fully charged Error tier battery
to charge such battery
we shall use an energy infuser
powered by the forbidden energy hatch that carries the power of a dozen of antimatter generators
and even with such power
it will still take a few minutes to charge up our battery
meanwhile
we managed to complete our first item with Star Gate in its name
this was a small step in our progression
but a huge leap in resource usage
so we added more astral array fabricators to our eye of harmony
thus making a lot of universium
and that is using half of our current power production
which in turn
is also using a quarter of our universium production
but
we have enough left over to slowly start building our star gate
and now we will be looking for all of the bottlenecks
such as that old HV fluid solidifier
or some crafting table recipes that are being done one at a time
luckily most of those have an assembler alternative
which of course we will parallelize
then we have machines that are still using small input buses
we shall move the used patterns to a proper crafting bus
also there are some invalid patterns laying around
due to stuff that didn't pass the beta tests
and we must not forget about doing some maintenance to our older setups
I mean we must not forget to upgrade everything
with the best technology at our disposal
finally we shall start adding more machines
where adding more power would start to make the consumption relevant
like our generic purpose parallel assembly line setup
which now will become multi machine parallel
and all of those assembly lines
reminded us of our circuit factory
which seems to start to struggle with the new demands
since it wasn't easy to expand that one
we made new factories
one for each circuit tier
and that was a lot of assembly lines
with a lot of expensive UXV energy hatches
and of course those are only assembling circuits
we needed a lot of other machines to keep up with all of the
circuit boards, memory, SMDs, cables, screws, weird materials
and everything else that goes into the circuits
and all of those machines are just the starting point of our Star Gate factory
which for now is a factory of UXV energy hatches
however
overclocking and building more machines isn't always the solution
our black hole had a special Redstone control
to optimize its crafting to last 3 minutes
the idea was to try to use the bonus parallel from the decaying black hole as much as possible
however
one of the Stargate parts requires an element that
even with overclocks
can't be made in less than a quarter of hour
since we don't want to have to wait that much for each recipe change
we had to make a second black hole
with special settings for that recipe
but the real issue here is the amount of space time required to keep a black hole open for that much time
since it doubles every 30 seconds
we are going to need almost 1 billion per second in the last phase
exactly half of the maximum we can input each update
which is also more than what an export bus can transfer
next since we were managing black holes
we also made a third one
this one will make eternal singularities passively with a timer circuit
finally
there is one last ingredient which we can't make yet
the Star Gate crystal
that one requires a special ingredient
graviton shards
the same we use for upgrading our gorge
and which we have none of
we have a button for retrieving those
but we first need to gather some
to do so
we have to reach more milestones
and the easiest one to do now is the composition one
this one requires us to add new modules or structure rings
so time to get an even cooler looking forge
and I know it looks majestic
and that we could stare at it for hours
but we have to move on
since we now have unlocked a bunch of Graviton Shards
actually there's more milestones we need to do
we can easily buy one with some universium
the fuel consumption was exponential with the transcendent residue
but it's not with constrained star matter
so we can just dump enough at once
to complete the fuel milestone
and that was probably not a good usage of fuel
however by unlocking all of the milestones
some new instructions appeared in our forge
and we now have enough graviton shards
to proceed with the mixing for the base dust required by the crystal
and after also doing some more stuff in our cyclotrons
we managed to get the dust
then we prepare some Stargate crystal slurry
and drop everything in a blast furnace
however
it looks like this recipe needs more heat
so we crank on the thermostat to the required temperature
and that is giving us a lot of boosts
finally
we also had to increase the processing power to start our crafting
and while the crystals were cooking
we noticed that our magmatter production wasn't working
upon a quick inspection
it looked like everything was in place
so let's get reminded of how that machine works
when we turn it on
we will get 2 fluids and a tiny dust
to get magmatter
we have to input back the two fluids and plasma of the material the tiny dust is made out of
that used to work fine
and allowed us to just shove everything the machine could possibly want to get the magmatter
however that feature has been patched
because it actually was a bug
and we now must input an amount of plasma that is exactly 144 times the difference between the other two fluids
and now we must find a way of automating that
we start by getting each one of the three starting outputs in a dedicated storage
then using the good old custom pattern trick
and the laggy crafting cards
we get out of there the two fluids in equal amounts
until only one is left
at that point
the fluid is moved to another tank
where a different subnetwork will trade each milliliter bucket for a cell
we send those cells to take the correct fluid selected by a Redstone contraption
thus having the correct amount of fluid for our magmatter
or so we thought
until we found out that cells carry a whole bucket
so we switched to the more precise volumetric flasks
that solved the mag matter issues
but we also have to find a solution for the quark gluon plasma fluid
which has some more possible materials in it
this time instead of overengineered Redstone setups
we shall use an even worse approach
we brute force the task using SFM
and since we couldn't find a solution on Stack Overflow
and we are afraid of for loops
we shall do a long chain of elseif
as in the programmer humor memes
but hey it works
anyways with that
we are now ready to start working on the craft of our star gate
that thing has many steps
and requires trillions of items
so we are going to split the task in more smaller ones
and while the small tasks are being done autonomously by AE2
we can work on improving our infrastructure
the first thing we shall fix is our power production
and of course that will need a lot of universium
which we can make with some astral arrays in a eye of harmony
then we build thousands of machines
to speed up the crafting of everything
finally
we overclock the slow stuff as much as our power production allows
cutting down the crafting time of the slowest parts by a factor of 1000
and now we have reached the TPS cap
so we just sit and watch our star gate being crafted
this took a lot of time
but we managed to slowly build it
and here we have our latest creation
however
while we completed the last quest of the mod pack
we aren't fully done yet
indeed
this device is useless if we don't have a second one
so we AFK a little bit more
while ae2 builds us a second one
after building it in some hidden place
we can connect to it by dialing its address in our main star gate
we confirm it and then we stare at the animation
and now it's time to show the mystical place this portal will bring us to
as you can see
this place has some weird green stuff spread across all over the place
but I think we did enough for today
we can try to think about touching this stuff in the next season
and as usual
before greetings
we shall reflect on what we Learned in today's episode
after all the drops of sweat and tears we did to make it this far
the real prize is not the reward we get from the quest completion
but the piles of stone dust we made along the way
bye bye
欢迎回来
今天我们要完成GTNH最后一个挑战
制作星门
它需要很多材料
有许多子步骤
但这一切都归结为三个主要部分
主要问题除了要使用昂贵材料
还有就是它们制作它们消耗的巨额时间
在合理的时间内制作这些东西
我们要做一些超频
而真正的问题是超频方案
如果不想跳电
或者几何级增长等待时间
我们必须找到最佳的折衷方案
要找到答案
我们首先要弄清楚
我们能产生多少能量
在寻找好的发电机的同时
我们的注意力被屏蔽拉格朗日湮灭矩阵吸引住了
一个依靠反物质发电的机器
当然
现在的问题是我们如何制造反物质
以及能做多少
结果证明
它是在一个需要复杂管理的多方块中产生的
半稳定反物质稳定定序器
快速建造它后
并获得一些反物质来启动机器
是时候找点乐子了
我们注意到的第一件也是最重要的事情是
我们必须让反物质均匀分布在各个仓室
而且这可不是儿戏
不管怎样
做一个小测试
我们首先把反物质分散到所有舱室
然后经过一系列测试
我们已经注意到必须时常提防是否有仓室缺少了反物质
在意识到一个简单的覆盖板是不够的之后
我们做了一个SFM程序
保证每个舱口都有固定数量的反物质
有了那个
我们现在可以慢慢制造一些反物质
然后我们将再次均匀地分布在所有舱口
我们留在机器里的反物质越多
我们生产的就越多
但也会使用更多的能量
现在的问题是
每个仓室应该放多少反物质
要得出答案
学校里上的微积分课就有了存在价值
根据每个仓室内的反物质数量来绘制能量函数
蓝线代表产生的反物质能产生多少能量
而红线会告诉我们消耗了多少能量
我们想最大化发电量
也就是两条线的差值
我们可以把它看成单一函数
在每个仓室里放两桶半反物质
我们能得到四个戴森球能量的最大发电量
然而
通过提高遏制稳定性
激活稳定化
重力稳定
磁稳定
我们设法让发电图超出屏幕
放大后
我们发现发电量现在可以达到600万亿 EU/t
此时每个仓室有4ML反物质
并需要添加一堆其他昂贵的东西
那是一个巨大的反物质球
将其转化为能量
我们还需要一台机器
这个比较简单
其中一个主要要求是给予其可平衡的材料
使用我们在鸿蒙之眼上用过的相同装置可以轻松解决
现在要优化的问题是
应该在每批中输入尽可能多的燃料
但限制在于激光仓的容量
使用16个UIV 100万A的激光源仓
发电量可以与100个戴森球相当
但是如果我们换成UMV 400万A
我们可以在5分钟内充满终极电池
这会导致很多问题
但解决每个问题的最好方法
就是使用更好的反应物
并打开无线模式
所以结论是
假设我们建立了一堆反物质序列
发电量将达到5千万亿 EU/t
一个有15个零的数字
从这个数字里
我们可以知道
可以将多少电输入进机器
有了那个
我们现在可以开始解决所有会在星门制作中出现的问题
就在着手于新能源生产时
第一个问题出现了
要想有高功率输出
我们必须在反物质定序器中输入各种液体来稳定它
而有些要么是昂贵的东西，要么是副产品
其中一种奇怪的流体是耗尽的硅岩燃料
在我们的燃料生产升级后
我们把备用发电机一直开着
但看起来这些燃料燃烧得不够快
所以我们不得不选择另一种方式来浪费燃料
中子活化超立方体
这是一个缓慢的过程
但幸运的是
我们为硅岩所准备的中子活化器
具有相同的动能工作范围
解决反物质生产材料后
我们也意识到，为了有效地反应
我们要消耗液态UMV超导粗胚
这里的主要问题是
这东西含有龙血
我们正在使用龙研聚合装置制作
那台机器有几个问题
第一个是像许多其他机器一样
它不接受多安能源仓
这意味着我们不能像用其他机器那样超频
这通常意味着我们只需要堆量
但还有第二个问题
每个机器都需要致密盖亚之魂大板
这意味着我们必须为阵列中的每台机器击败两个以上的惹人厌的植物魔法的boss
然而
在做那个烦人的任务时
某种东西让我们灵光一现
似乎有个怪有很高的几率掉率刷怪蛋
用这些我们可以制作龙蛋
通过普通的搅拌可以变成龙血
我们要做的就是找到正确的怪物
并进行工业化生产
这样我们就可以生产大量的刷怪蛋
龙蛋
还有龙血
现在我们已经修好了发电
是时候制作一些能源仓来充分利用它了
这里
我们意识到宇宙素的产量太低了
解决这个问题
我们需要再做几个星阵
现在的问题是CPU的大小
所以我想是时候做一个奇点合成存储单元了
如果我们想多做一些
我们得去干掉些混沌守卫
每干掉一个
便可以得到一个有8EB存储空间的合成单元
现在缺少的是并行单元
相反，我们将开始优化样板
使用新的样板优化矩阵
这是因为并行能增加每秒完成的制作步骤的数量
不过与其多走几步
不如跨大脚步
为此
我们借助优化矩阵将模板相乘
这将使最大步骤控制在我们设定的数量内
然而
这样做也会造成很多冗余
我们的存储元件已经被填满了
所以我们要升级到人造宇宙版
制造其中一个需要充满电的error等级电池
要给它充电
我们将使用能量注入器
由携带十几个反物质发生器的能量的禁忌能量仓供电
即使有这样的电力
给电池充电仍然需要几分钟
同时
我们已经完成了第一个带有星门名字的物品了
这只是我们进步的一小步
但是是资源使用的巨大飞跃
所以我们在鸿蒙之眼中添加了更多星阵
这会产出大量宇宙素
而这也使用了目前一半的电力生产
反过来
它也使用了四分之一的宇宙素
但是
用于制作星门的量还是绰绰有余
现在我们将寻找所有的瓶颈
比如那个旧的HV流体固化器
或者一些一次只做一个的样板
幸运的是，其中大多数都有组装机配方
我们当然会让它们能够并行生产
然后我们有机器仍然使用小型输入总线
我们把使用过的样板转移到正确的总成中
而这也有些无效样板
因为其没活过测试版
我们不能忘记对旧设备进行一些维护
意思是应该全部进行升级
用我们掌握的最好的技术
最后我们将开始添加更多机器
直到加更多能源会造成不容小看的电量消耗
就像我们的通用并行装配线设置一样
现在将成为多机并行
所有这些装配线
让我们想起了电路工厂
它似乎跟不上新的需求了
扩展这个可不简单
我们建造了新工厂
每个电路一个
这可是很多装配线
有很多昂贵的UXV能源仓
当然，这些只用来组装电路
我们需要很多其他机器来跟上所有的
电路板、内存、SMD、电缆、螺丝、奇怪的材料
以及其他装配电路的东西
所有这些机器只是我们星门工厂的起点
而工厂已全面装设UXV能源仓
然而
超频和制造更多机器并不总是解决方案
我们的黑洞有一个特殊的红石控制装置
将其合成优化到持续3分钟
宗旨是尽可能多地利用衰变黑洞奖励的并行
然而
星门部件的一部分
即使有超频
至少需要15分钟制作
因为我们不想每次更换配方都要等那么久
我们必须制造第二个黑洞
此配方有个特殊设置
但真正的问题是要保持此黑洞开启所需要的大量时空
因为它每30秒翻倍一次
在最后阶段我们需要每秒10亿
正好是我们每次更新可以输入的最大值的一半
这也比输出仓能转移的多
接下来，既然我们在做黑洞的东西
我们还做了第三个
这个会用计时器电路被动制造永恒奇点
最后
还有最后一种成分我们做不出来
星门水晶
它需要特殊材料
引力子碎片
和我们用来升级神锻的一样
而我们一个都没有
我们有一个用于提取引力子碎片的按钮
但我们首先需要收集一些
为此
我们必须达到更多的里程碑
现在最简单的是结构
这个需要我们添加新的模块或环
所以是时候换一个更酷的外观了
我知道它看起来很壮观
我们可以看它旋转几小时
但我们必须继续前进
因为我们已经解锁了一堆引力子碎片
事实上，我们需要做更多的里程碑
我们可以很容易地用一些宇宙素买到一个
燃料消耗与超维度残留成指数关系
但对于蓝框岩浆可不是
所以我们可以一次输入足够多的燃料
完成燃料里程碑
这可能不是一个正确的燃料用途
但是通过解锁所有里程碑
我们的神锻里出现了一些新的指示
我们现在有足够的引力子碎片
用于混合出星门水晶所需的基础粉尘
在回旋加速器中做了更多的事情之后
我们弄到了所需的粉
然后我们准备一些星门水晶浆液
并把所有东西扔进高炉
然而
看起来这个配方需要更高的炉温
所以我们把炉温调制要求值
这给了我们很大的提升
最后
我们还必须增加处理电压来开始制作
当水晶在烹饪的时候
我们注意到磁物质未能正常生产
经过快速检查
看起来一切都就位了
让我们来看看这台机器是如何工作的
当我们打开它时
我们会得到2种液体和一种小撮粉
得到磁物质
我们必须输入两种液体和小撮粉对应的等离子体
之前一切正常
允许我们供给机器可能想要的所有材料
但是这个特性已经被修复了
因为那其实是bug
我们现在必须输入的等离子量正好是另外两种液体差的144倍
现在我们必须找到一种自动化的方法
我们首先将三个起始输出中的每一个都放入专用存储中
然后使用古老的自定义模板技巧
还有略卡顿的合成卡
我们从那里取出等量的两种液体
直到只剩下一种
到那时
液体被转移到另一个罐中
其中，不同的子网络将把每个毫升交换出一个空单元
我们把单元通过红石装置来获取正确的液体输入
从而为我们的磁物质提供正确数量的液体
或许我们是这么想的
直到我们发现空单元一次必须装一桶
所以我们改用更精确的容积瓶
这解决了磁物质问题
但是我们也必须完成夸克胶子等离子体的自动化
生产它有更多可以使用的材料
这次不是过度开发的红石装置
我们将使用更糟糕的方法
我们使用SFM暴力完成任务
既然我们在Stack Overflow上找不到解决方案
我们害怕for循环
我们将做一长串的else if
就像程序员幽默meme一样
拜托，能跑就行
不管怎样
我们现在着手制作星门
那东西有很多步骤
并需要数万亿件物品
所以我们将任务抽丝剥茧
当AE自动完成任务的时候
我们可以致力于改善基础设施
我们首先要解决的是电力生产
当然，这需要很多宇宙素
我们可以用一些星阵加速它
然后我们制造成千上万的机器
加快一切的制作
最后
我们尽可能多地超频慢速的东西
将最慢零件的制作时间缩短1000倍
现在我们已经达到了TPS上限
所以我们就坐在那里看着星门被制作出来
这花了很多时间
但我们设法慢慢建造了它
这是我们最新的造物
然而
当我们完成整合包的最后一个任务时
我们还没有完全完成
确实
如果没有第二套门，这个设备就没用了
所以我们再挂机一会儿
等待AE为我们再造一个
在某个隐蔽的地方建造后
我们在主星门通过拨号它的地址来连接它
我们确认了一下，然后盯着动画
现在是时候展示这个入口带我们去的神秘地方了
如你所见
这个地方到处都是奇怪的绿色东西
但我觉得我们今天做得够多了
我们可以考虑下一季再碰这些东西
和往常一样
问候前
我们将反思今天学到的东西
经过我们所有的汗水和泪水才走到这一步
真正的奖励不是任务完成后的奖励
而是我们一路上做出的石头粉
拜拜